<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<Course>
	<Divide>Labratory</Divide>
	<Department>Biology</Department>
	<Prefix>BIOL</Prefix>
	<Number>1407</Number>
	<Name>General Biology II</Name>
	<Description>
	A continuation of Biology 1406. Topics include evolution and
	diversity of invertebrate and vertebrate animals; mechanism of support and
	movement, digestion and nutrition, respiration, circulation homeostasis,
	hormonal control, nervous control, sexual reproduction, development, behavior
	and ecology. Credit Restriction: Credit may be received in only one of
	BIOL 1407 or BIOL 1488.
	</Description>
	<Credit-hours>4.000 Credit Hours</Credit-hours>
	<Lecture-hours>3.000 Lecture hours</Lecture-hours>
	<Lab-hours>3.000</Lab-hours>
	<Level>Undergraduate</Level>
	<Schedule-type>Lecture, Laboratory</Schedule-type>
	<Prerequisite>None</Prerequisite>
	<Co-requisite>None</Co-requisite>
	<Legacy-number>None</Legacy-number>
	<Cross-listed>None</Cross-listed>
	<Restrictions>None</Restrictions>
	<Course-attributes>Core Life and Phys Sciences-030, Lab fee - Biology</Course-attributes>
	<ABET-outcomes>
		(a) An ability to apply knowledge of computing and mathematics
		appropriate to the discipline.
		(b) An ability to analyze a problem, and identify and define the
		computing requirements appropriate to its solution.
		(c) An ability to design, implement, and evaluate a computer-based
		system, process, component, or program to meet desired needs.
		(i) An ability to use current techniques, skills, and tools necessary
		for computing practice.
		(j) An ability to apply mathematical foundations, algorithmic principles,
		and computer Science theory in the modeling and design of computer-based systems
		in a way that demonstrates comprehension of the tradeoffs involved in design choices.
		(k) An ability to apply design and development principles in the construction
		of software systems of varying complexity.
	</ABET-outcomes>
	<Learning-outcomes>
		1). To understand and apply method and appropriate technology to the study of natural sciences.
		2). To recognize scientific and quantitative methods and the differences between these
		approaches and other methods of inquiry and to communicate findings, analyses, and interpretation 
		both orally and in writing.
		3). To identify and recognize the differences among competing scientific theories.
		4). To demonstrate knowledge of the major issues and problems facing modern
		science, including issues that touch upon ethics, values, and public policies.
		5). To demonstrate knowledge of the interdependence of science and technology and
		their influence on, and contribution to, modern culture.
	</Learning-outcomes>
</Course>
