<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Course>
	<Divide>Technical Electives</Divide>
	<Department>Computer Science</Department>
	<Prefix>CSCI</Prefix>
	<Number>4318</Number>
	<Name>Cyber Security</Name>
	<Description>This course explores cyber security fundamentals, standards of good practice, and basic theory in depth. Topics will include privacy, confidentiality, integrity, and encryption. Key areas include network attacks and defenses, operating systems flaws, malware, social engineering and digital rights management.</Description>
	<Credit-hours>3.000 Credit hours</Credit-hours>
	<Lecture-hours>3.000 Lecture hours</Lecture-hours>
	<Lab-hours>0.000 Lab hours</Lab-hours>
	<Level>Undergraduate</Level>
	<Schedule-type>Lecture</Schedule-type>
	<Prerequisite>CSCI-2344,SCI-3333/CMPE-3333</Prerequisite>
	<Co-requisite>None</Co-requisite>
	<Legacy-number>None</Legacy-number>
	<Cross-listed>None</Cross-listed>
	<Restrictions>None</Restrictions>
	<Course-attributes>CS Instruction Fee - HU</Course-attributes>
	<ABET-outcomes>
	  (a) An ability to apply knowledge of computing and mathematics appropriate to
	  the program's student outcomes and to the discipline.
	  (b) An ability to analyze a problem, and identify and define the computing
	  requirements appropriate to its solution.
	  (c) An Ability to design, implement, and evaluate a computer-based systemprocess,
	  component, or program to meet desired needs.
	  (d) An ability to function effectively on teams to accomplish a common goal.
	  (e) An understanding of professional, ethical, legal, security and social issues
	  and responsibilities.
	  (f) An ability to communicate effectively with a range of audiences.
	  (g) An ability to analyze the local and global impact of computing on individuals,
	  organizations, and society.
	  (i) An ability to use current techniques, skills, and tools necesary for computing
	  practice.
	  (j) An ability to apply mathematical foundations, algorithmic principles, and computer
	  science theory in the modeling and design of computer-based systems in a way that demonstrates
	  comprehension of the tradeoffs involved in design choices.
	</ABET-outcomes>
	<Learning-outcomes>
		1. Understand the basic theory and concepts of cyber security and privacy including policies, models, and mechanisms
		2. Understand ethics, legal issues, and human factors associated with cyber security and forensic
		3. Understand security vulnerabilities and be able to describe threats and risks directed at computer hardware and software and recognize and categorize network vulnerabilities and attacks
		4. Be able to explain best practices in giving access to systems and networks and implement proper authentication techniques.
		5. Be familiar with cryptographic techniques, asymmetric key algorithms, and create certificates.
	  6. Describe the requirements for a cyber forensic investigation and demonstrate an understanding of tools, techniques and procedures
		7. Be conversant in current security-related issues in the fields of cyber security and cyber forensics.
	</Learning-outcomes>


</Course>
