<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>

<Course>
	<Divide>Technical Electives</Divide>
	<Department>Computer Science</Department>
	<Prefix>CSCI</Prefix>
	<Number>4365</Number>
	<Name>Computer and Network Security</Name>
	<Description>
		This course examines the internetworking architecture and routing, design and implementation issues related to secure and reliable networks, cryptography, firewalls, digital signatures, worms, viruses, logic bombs and spyware. Equivalent course: CMPE 4363. A student may receive credit only in one course.
	</Description>
	<Credit-hours>3.000 Credit hours</Credit-hours>
	<Lecture-hours>3.000 Lecture hours</Lecture-hours>
	<Lab-hours>0.000 Lab hours</Lab-hours>
	<Level>Undergraduate</Level>
	<Schedule-type>Lecture</Schedule-type>
	<Prerequisite>
		CSCI-4345,
		CMPE-4345
	</Prerequisite>
	<Co-requisite>None</Co-requisite>
	<Legacy-number>None</Legacy-number>
	<Cross-listed>None</Cross-listed>
	<Restrictions>None</Restrictions>
	<Course-attributes>None</Course-attributes>
	<ABET-outcomes>
	  (a) An ability to apply knowledge of computing and mathematics appropriate to
	  the program's student outcomes and to the discipline.
	  (b) An ability to analyze a problem, and identify and define the computin
	  requirements appropriate to its solution.
	  (c) An Ability to design, implement, and evaluate a computer-based system, process,
	  component, or program to meet desired needs.
	  (d) An ability to function effectively on teams to accomplish a common goal.
	  (e) An understanding of professional, ethical, legal, security and social issues
	  and responsibilities.
	  (f) An ability to communicate effectively with a range of audiences.
	  (h) Recognition of the need for and an ability to engage in continuing professional
	  development
	  (i) An ability to use current techniques, skills, and tools necesary for computing
	  practice.
	  (k) An ability to apply design and development principles in the construction of
	  software systems of varifying complexity.
	</ABET-outcomes>
	<Learning-outcomes>
	  1 Demonstrate understanding of the fundamental concepts of data communications
	  2 Understand signals and signal encoding methods to communications and data transmission modes.
	  3 Describe, compare and contrast the five (TCP/IP) or seven layers (OSI) models of networking and their functionalities
	  4 Explain an implement application layer protocols in a high level language such as C/C++ or Java.
	  5 Explain the basic concepts of reliable transport.
	  6 Explain the basic concepts of the network, link and physical layers and be able to configure routers,
	    switches, hubs and repeaters.
	  7 Design and build a network application including client-server and peer-to-peer.
	  8 Setup networking specific software such as Routing tables, DNS, Mail servers, DHCP, and wireless
	    network
	  9 Describe emerging technologies in the net-centric computing area and assess their current capabilities,
	    limitations, and near-term potential
	</Learning-outcomes>

</Course>
