<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<Course>
	<Divide>Technical Electives</Divide>
	<Department>Computer Science</Department>
	<Prefix>CSCI</Prefix>
	<Number>4302</Number>
	<Name>Multimedia Systems</Name>
	<Description>
		This course presents the broad field of multimedia systems. Topics include the digital interactive
		multimedia, creation of multimedia, and various issues involving technology, design and effectiveness of multimedia
		applications. Students will have the opportunity to learn programming techniques for integrating video, sound, animation
		and graphics for multimedia systems.
	</Description>
	<Credit-hours>3.000 Credit hours</Credit-hours>
	<Lecture-hours>3.000 Lecture hours</Lecture-hours>
	<Lab-hours>0.000 Lab hours</Lab-hours>
	<Level>Undergraduate</Level>
	<Schedule-type>Lecture</Schedule-type>
	<Prerequisite> Undergraduate level CSCI 3333/CMPE 3333 with a minimum grade of D or consent of instructor.
	</Prerequisite>
	<Co-requisite>None</Co-requisite>
	<Legacy-number>None</Legacy-number>
	<Cross-listed>None</Cross-listed>
	<Restrictions>dnu-MED in Educational Admin, MPA in Public Administration, Bus. Admin -Accelerated online, and not in English Language Institute level
	</Restrictions>
	<Course-attributes>
		Degree Elective, CS Instruction Fee - HU
	</Course-attributes>
	<ABET-outcomes>
	  (a) An ability to apply knowledge of computing and mathematics appropriate to
	  the program's student outcomes and to the discipline.
	  (b) An ability to analyze a problem, and identify and define the computing
	  requirements appropriate to its solution.
	  (c) An Ability to design, implement, and evaluate a computer-based system, process,
	  component, or program to meet desired needs.
	  (i) An ability to use current techniques, skills, and tools necesary for computing
	  practice.
	  (j) An ability to apply mathematical foundations, algorithmic principles, and computer
	  science theory in the modeling and design of computer-based systems in a way that demonstrates
	  comprehension of the tradeoffs involved in design choices.
	  (k) An ability to apply design and development principles in the construction of
	  software systems of varifying complexity.
	</ABET-outcomes>
	<Learning-outcomes>
	</Learning-outcomes>

</Course>
