<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>

<Course>
  <Divide>Technical Electives</Divide>
  <Department>Computer Science</Department>
  <Prefix>CSCI</Prefix>
  <Number>4350</Number>
  <Name>Artificial Intelligence</Name>
  <Description>
  Study of intelligent machines and machine learning. Includes problem solving and heuristic search, natural language understanding,
    game playing, database and expert systems. Artificial Intelligence projects will be implemented using an AI language such as LISP,
    Prolog, C++ or Ada.
  </Description>
  <Credit-hours>3.000 Credit hours</Credit-hours>
  <Lecture-hours>3.000 Lecture hours</Lecture-hours>
  <Lab-hours>0.000 Lab hours</Lab-hours>
  <Level>Undergraduate</Level>
  <Schedule-type>Lecture</Schedule-type>
  <Prerequisite>CSCI-3333/CMPE-3333</Prerequisite>
  <Co-requisite>None</Co-requisite>
  <Legacy-number>COSC-4350</Legacy-number>
  <Cross-listed>CMPE-4350</Cross-listed>
  <Restrictions>Senior or Junior standing</Restrictions>
  <Course-attributes>
      Degree Elective,
      CS Instruction Fee - HU
 </Course-attributes>
 <ABET-outcomes>
   (a) An ability to apply knowledge of computing and mathematics appropriate to
   the program's student outcomes and to the discipline.
   (b) An ability to analyze a problem, and identify and define the computing
   requirements appropriate to its solution.
   (c) An Ability to design, implement, and evaluate a computer-based system, process,
   component, or program to meet desired needs.
   (d) An ability to function effectively on teams to accomplish a common goal.
   (e) An understanding of professional, ethical, legal, security and social issues
   and responsibilities.
   (f) An ability to communicate effectively with a range of audiences.
   (g) An ability to analyze the local and global impact of computing on individuals,
   organizations, and society.
   (i) An ability to use current techniques, skills, and tools necesary for computing
   practice
   (k) An ability to apply design and development principles in the construction of
   software systems of varifying complexity.
 </ABET-outcomes>
 <Learning-outcomes>
     <item>Introduction
         <item2>Evaluate AI techniques and synthesize solutions to practical examples.</item2>
         <item2>Develop a range of typical applications using artificial intelligence methods.</item2>
         <item2>Demonstrate problem-solving skills.</item2>
     </item>
     <item>History and philosophy of artificial intelligence
         <item2>Define weak and strong AI and provide some arguments for and against each hypothesis.</item2>
         <item2>Discuss accomplishments of artificial intelligence research in historical context.</item2>
         <item2>Discuss the concept of rationality.</item2>
     </item>
     <item>Problem solving in artificial intelligence
         <item2>Explain classical search algorithms, including breadth-first, depth-first, A*, and heuristic search.</item2>
         <item2>Implement classical search algorithms.</item2>
         <item2>Discuss local search algorithms and their applications to finding goals and in optimization problems.</item2>
     </item>
     <item>Knowledge and reasoning
         <item2>Understand key concepts related to Knowledge representation.</item2>
     </item>
     <item>Uncertain Knowledge and reasoning
         <item2>Discuss the influence of uncertainty on decision-making.</item2>
         <item2>Understand and apply the terminology and notation of basic probability.</item2>
         <item2>Understand and apply Bayes' rule.</item2>
         <item2>Solve simple probability problems.</item2>
     </item>
     <item>Machine Learning
         <item2>Define supervised and unsupervised learning.</item2>
         <item2>Discuss learning decision trees.</item2>
         <item2>Understand the principles of neural networks.</item2>
         <item2>Understand statistical learning methods, including Naive Bayes.</item2>
         <item2>Understand reinforcement learning methods and selected algorithms.</item2>
         <item2>Discuss the applications of machine learning to domains such as game playing.</item2>
         <item2>Implement selected machine learning algorithms.</item2>
     </item>
     <item>Evolutionary computation
         <item2>Discuss the key elements of evolutionary computation methods.</item2>
         <item2>Compare and contrast different evolutionary methods, such as genetic algorithms and digital evolution.</item2>
     </item>
 </Learning-outcomes>



</Course>
