<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<Course>
  <Divide>Computer Science Core</Divide>
<Department>Computer Science</Department>
<Prefix>CSCI</Prefix>
<Number>2344</Number>
<Name>Programming in a UNIX/Linux Envr</Name>
<Description>The course presents the UNIX file system, the commonly used utilities, editors, shell programming and scripting. It includes instruction in software development in the UNIX/Linux environment. In addition, a brief overview of the internal components of the operating system will be covered.</Description>
<Credit-hours>3.000 Credit hours</Credit-hours>
<Lecture-hours>3.000 Lecture hours</Lecture-hours>
<Lab-hours>0.000 Lab hours</Lab-hours>
<Level>Undergraduate</Level>
<Schedule-type>Lecture</Schedule-type>
  <Prerequisite>CSCI-1370/CMPE-1370 or CSCI-1378/CMPE-1378 or consent of instructor
  </Prerequisite>
  <Co-requisite>None</Co-requisite>
<Legacy-number>None</Legacy-number>
<Cross-listed>None</Cross-listed>
	<Restrictions>
  		dnu-MED in Educational Admin,
  		MPA in Public Administration,
  		Bus. Admin -Accelerated online
	</Restrictions>
	<Course-attributes>
		Degree Elective,
	  CS Instruction Fee - LU
</Course-attributes>
<ABET-outcomes>
  (a) An ability to apply knowledge of computing and mathematics appropriate to
  the program's student outcomes and to the discipline.
  (b) An ability to analyze a problem, and identify and define the computing
  requirements appropriate to its solution.
  (c) An Ability to design, implement, and evaluate a computer-based system, process,
  component, or program to meet desired needs.
  (d) An ability to function effectively on teams to accomplish a common goal.
  (i) An ability to use current techniques, skills, and tools necesary for computing
  practice.
</ABET-outcomes>
<Learning-outcomes>
	1. Understand the objectives and functions of Unix/Linux operating systems
	2. Understand how operating systems have evolved over time from primitive batch systems to sophisticated multi-user systems
	3. Understand Unix/Linux file system, file processing, and file security
	4. Use basic and advance Unix commands
	5. Use Unix/Linux utilities
	6. Use basic editors, such as vi or emacs, on Unix/Linux environment
	7. Program with shell script languages
	8. Develop Unix/Linux applications in C/C++
</Learning-outcomes>


</Course>
