<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<Course>
  <Divide>Technical Electives</Divide>
  <Department>Computer Science</Department>
  <Prefix>CSCI</Prefix>
  <Number>3342</Number>
  <Name>Internet Programming</Name>
  <Description>
    Introduction to web application programming. Covers the fundamentals of developing
    applications for web browsers, within the dominant HTTP-based client/server model.
    A wide range of technologies and development methodologies are covered, including database
    and server architectures, serer-side frameworks, client-side languages/libraries, remote
    invocation models and web application security. Specific topics in web development change
    rapidly, but some examples include SQL, HTML, TLS, PHP, Java EE (servllets, JSP, etc),
    ASP.NET.
  </Description>
  <Credit-hours>3.000 Credit hours</Credit-hours>
  <Lecture-hours>3.000 Lecture hours</Lecture-hours>
  <Lab-hours>0.000 Lab hours</Lab-hours>
  <Level>Undergraduate</Level>
  <Schedule-type>Lecture</Schedule-type>
  <Prerequisite>
    CSCI-2380/CSCI-2388 or CMPE-2380/CMPE-2388,
    CSCI-3327 or CSCI-3328
  </Prerequisite>
  <Co-requisite>
    CMPE-3341
  </Co-requisite>
  <Legacy-number>COSC-4346</Legacy-number>
  <Cross-listed>
    CMPE-3342
  </Cross-listed>
  <Restrictions>
    dnu-MED in Educational Admin,
    MPA in Public Administration ,
    Bus. Admin -Accelerated online,
    May not be enrolled in English Language Institute
  </Restrictions>
  <Course-attributes>Degree Elective, CS Instruction Fee – HU
  </Course-attributes>
  <ABET-outcomes>
    (a) An ability to apply knowledge of computing and mathematics appropriate to
    the program's student outcomes and to the discipline.
    (b) An ability to analyze a problem, and identify and define the computing
    requirements appropriate to its solution.
    (c) An Ability to design, implement, and evaluate a computer-based system, process,
    component, or program to meet desired needs.
    (d) An ability to function effectively on teams to accomplish a common goal.
    (e) An understanding of professional, ethical, legal, security and social issues
    and responsibilities.
    (h) Recognition of the need for and an ability to engage in continuing professional
    development
    (i) An ability to use current techniques, skills, and tools necesary for computing
    practice.
    (k) An ability to apply design and development principles in the construction of
    software systems of varifying complexity.
  </ABET-outcomes>
  <Learning-outcomes>
    1. Understand how web technologies interact, from the browser to the backend servers.
    2. Gain familiarity with numerous languages and standard protocols.
    3. Learn database design basics and SQL access.
    4. Implement dynamic content web pages using two- and three-tier architectures.
    5. Become familiar with the range of browser application clients
    6. Gain practical experience in a selected set of Web technologies.
    7. Learn how to keep pace with the rapidly changing landscape of web application developmen
    8. Implement a web application with database content and a dynamic client.
  </Learning-outcomes>


</Course>
