<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<Course>
<Divide>Technical Electives</Divide>
<Department>Computer Science</Department>
<Prefix>CSCI</Prefix>
<Number>3370 </Number>
<Name>Intro Game Develop</Name>
<Description>
This is a project based course in which programmers and designers collaborate to create a video game. The course investigates theory and practice of developing computer games from a variety of perspectives.
</Description>
<Credit-hours>3.000 Credit hours</Credit-hours>
<Lecture-hours>3.000 Lecture hours</Lecture-hours>
<Lab-hours>0.000 Lab hours</Lab-hours>
<Level>Undergraduate</Level>
<Schedule-type>Lecture</Schedule-type>
 <Prerequisite>
  CSCI-3333/CMPE-3333, CSCI-3326/CMPE 3326 or CSCI-3327/CMPE 3327 or CSCI-3328/CMPE-3328 or consent of instructor
 </Prerequisite>
  <Co-requisite>None</Co-requisite>
<Legacy-number>None</Legacy-number>
<Cross-listed>None</Cross-listed>
	<Restrictions>None</Restrictions>
<Course-attributes>Degree Elective, CS Instruction Fee - HU</Course-attributes>
<ABET-outcomes>
  (a) An ability to apply knowledge of computing and mathematics appropriate to
  the program's student outcomes and to the discipline.
  (b) An ability to analyze a problem, and identify and define the computing
  requirements appropriate to its solution.
  (c) An Ability to design, implement, and evaluate a computer-based system, process,
  component, or program to meet desired needs.
  (d) An ability to function effectively on teams to accomplish a common goal.
  (i) An ability to use current techniques, skills, and tools necesary for computing
  practice.
  (j) An ability to apply mathematical foundations, algorithmic principles, and computer
  science theory in the modeling and design of computer-based systems in a way that demonstrates
  comprehension of the tradeoffs involved in design choices.
  (k) An ability to apply design and development principles in the construction of
  software systems of varifying complexity.
</ABET-outcomes>
<Learning-outcomes>
</Learning-outcomes>

</Course>
