<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>


<Course>
	<Divide>Technical Electives</Divide>
	<Department>Computer Science</Department>
	<Prefix>CSCI</Prefix>
	<Number>4383</Number>
	<Name>Bioinformatics Imaging</Name>
	<Description>
		This course provides an introduction to the physical and computational principles of medical imaging systems.
		Topics covered include fundamentals of x-ray radiography, x-ray computed tomography, ultrasound imaging and
		magnetic resonance imaging. Current techniques for visualization, segmentation, and analysis of medical image
		data will be discussed.
	</Description>
	<Credit-hours>3.000 Credit hours</Credit-hours>
	<Lecture-hours>3.000 Credit hours</Lecture-hours>
	<Lab-hours>0.000 Credit hours</Lab-hours>
	<Level>Undergraduate</Level>
	<Schedule-type>Lecture</Schedule-type>
	<Prerequisite>
		CSCI 3333 or
		CMPE 3333 or
		Consent of the instructor
	</Prerequisite>
	<Co-requisite>
		None
	</Co-requisite>
	<Legacy-number>COSC-4382</Legacy-number>
	<Cross-listed>None</Cross-listed>
	<Restrictions>None</Restrictions>
	<Course-attributes>None</Course-attributes>
	<ABET-outcomes>
	  <item> (a) An ability to apply knowledge of computing and mathematics appropriate to
	  the program's student outcomes and to the discipline.</item>
	  <item> (b) An ability to analyze a problem, and identify and define the computing
	  requirements appropriate to its solution.</item>
	  <item> (c) An Ability to design, implement, and evaluate a computer-based system, process,
	  component, or program to meet desired needs.</item>
	  <item> (i) An ability to use current techniques, skills, and tools necesary for computing
	  practice.</item>
	  <item> (j) An ability to apply mathematical foundations, algorithmic principles, and computer
	  science theory in the modeling and design of computer-based systems in a way that demonstrates
	  comprehension of the tradeoffs involved in design choices.</item>
	  <item> (k) An ability to apply design and development principles in the construction of
	  software systems of varifying complexity.</item>
	</ABET-outcomes>
	<Learning-outcomes></Learning-outcomes>
</Course>
