<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>

<Course>
	<Divide>Technical Electives</Divide>
	<Department>Computer Science</Department>
	<Prefix>CSCI</Prefix>
	<Number>4365</Number>
	<Name>Computer and Network Security</Name>
	<Description>
		This course examines the internetworking architecture and routing, design and implementation issues related to secure and reliable networks, cryptography, firewalls, digital signatures, worms, viruses, logic bombs and spyware. Equivalent course: CMPE 4363. A student may receive credit only in one course.
	</Description>
	<Credit-hours>3.000 Credit hours</Credit-hours>
	<Lecture-hours>3.000 Lecture hours</Lecture-hours>
	<Lab-hours>0.000 Lab hours</Lab-hours>
	<Level>Undergraduate</Level>
	<Schedule-type>Lecture</Schedule-type>
	<Prerequisite>
		CSCI-4345
		CMPE-4345
	</Prerequisite>
	<Co-requisite>None</Co-requisite>
	<Legacy-number>None</Legacy-number>
	<Cross-listed>None</Cross-listed>
	<Restrictions>None</Restrictions>
	<Course-attributes>None</Course-attributes>
	<ABET-outcomes>
	  (a) An ability to apply knowledge of computing and mathematics appropriate to
	  the program's student outcomes and to the discipline.
	  (b) An ability to analyze a problem, and identify and define the computing
	  requirements appropriate to its solution.
	  (c) An Ability to design, implement, and evaluate a computer-sed system, process,
	  component, or program to meet desired needs.
	  (d) An ability to function effectively on teams to accomplish a common goal.
	  (e) An understanding of professional, ethical, legal, security and social issues
	  and responsibilities.
	  (f) An ability to communicate effectively with a range of audiences.
	  (g) An ability to analyze the local and global impact of computing on individuals,
	  organizations, and society.
	  (i) An ability to use current techniques, skills, and tools necesary for computing
	  practice.
	  (j) An ability to apply mathematical foundations, algorithmic principles, and computer 
	  science theory in the modeling and design of computer-based systems in a way that demonstrates
	  comprehension of the tradeoffs involved in design choices.
	</ABET-outcomes>

</Course>
