<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Course>
	<Divide>Mathematics and Engineering</Divide>
	<Department>Mathematics</Department>
	<Prefix>MATH</Prefix>
	<Number>2414</Number>
	<Name>Calculus II</Name>
	<Description>
    Topics include derivatives and integrals of transcendental functions, methods of
integration, parameterized curves, integration in polar coordinates, and infinite
sequences and series.
  </Description>
	<Credit-hours>4.000 Credit hours</Credit-hours>
	<Lecture-hours>4.000 Lecture hours</Lecture-hours>
	<Lab-hours>0.000 Lab hours</Lab-hours>
	<Level>Undergraduate</Level>
	<Schedule-type>Lecture</Schedule-type>
	<Prerequisite><item>MATH-1460 or appropriate high school background and placement scores</item></Prerequisite>
	<Co-requisite><item>None</item></Co-requisite>
	<Legacy-number>None</Legacy-number>
	<Cross-listed>None</Cross-listed>
	<Restrictions><item>None</item></Restrictions>
	<Course-attributes><item>CS Instruction Fee - HU</item><item>Degree Elective</item></Course-attributes>
	<ABET-outcomes>
	    <item> (a) An ability to apply knowledge of computing and mathematics appropriate to the discipline.</item>
	    <item> (j) An ability to apply mathematical foundations, algorithmic principles, and computer science
	    theory in the modeling and design of computer-based systems in a way that demonstrates comprehension of
	    the tradeoffs involved in design choices.</item>
	</ABET-outcomes>
	<Learning-outcomes>
		<item>Correctly apply the standard methods of integration, including substitution,
	integration by parts, trigonometric identities, trigonometric substitution, and
	partial fraction decomposition</item>
	  <item>Approximate definite integrals using the Riemann sums, trapezoid rule, Simpson's
	rule, and series techniques</item>
	  <item>Properly define and evaluate improper integrals and apply the Comparison Test to
	determine whether they converge or diverge</item>
	  <item>Apply integration to compute areas, volumes, work, average values of functions,
	arc lengths, surface areas, hydrostatic pressures and forces, centers of mass, and
	moments.
	</item>
	  <item>Define curves parametrically and in polar coordinates, and perform the standard
	calculus computations on parametric and polar curves, such as derivatives,
	integrals, areas, arc lengths, and surface areas.</item>
	  <item>Understand the concepts of sequence, series, limits of sequences and series,
	convergence and divergence of sequences and series, and absolute and conditional
	convergence of series</item>
	  <item>Compute power, Taylor, and Maclaurin polynomials and series for a function, and
	apply these ideas to problems in mathematics, science, and engineering</item>
	</Learning-outcomes>

</Course>
