<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Course>
	<Divide>Mathematics and Engineering</Divide>
	<Department>Mathematics</Department>
	<Prefix>MATH</Prefix>
	<Number>3331</Number>
	<Name>Applied Statistics</Name>
	<Description>
    This course concerns itself with probabilistic models, regression analysis,
    nonparametric statistics, and the basics of experimental design. Computer laboratory
    experience will be an important part of the course.
  </Description>
	<Credit-hours>4.000 Credit hours</Credit-hours>
	<Lecture-hours>4.000 Lecture hours</Lecture-hours>
	<Lab-hours>0.000 Lab hours</Lab-hours>
	<Level>Undergraduate</Level>
	<Schedule-type>Lecture</Schedule-type>
	<Prerequisite><item>Junior Standing</item>
  <item>MATH-1340 or MATH-1341</item>
  </Prerequisite>
	<Co-requisite><item>None</item></Co-requisite>
	<Legacy-number>None</Legacy-number>
	<Cross-listed>None</Cross-listed>
	<Restrictions><item>None</item></Restrictions>

	<Course-attributes><item>CS Instruction Fee - HU</item><item>Degree Elective</item></Course-attributes>
	<ABET-outcomes>
	  <item> (a) An ability to apply knowledge of computing and mathematics appropriate to
	  the program's student outcomes and to the discipline.</item>
	  <item> (b) An ability to analyze a problem, and identify and define the computing
	  requirements appropriate to its solution.</item>
	  <item> (i) An ability to use current techniques, skills, and tools necesary for computing
	  practice.</item>
	  <item> (j) An ability to apply mathematical foundations, algorithmic principles, and computer
	  science theory in the modeling and design of computer-based systems in a way that demonstrates
	  comprehension of the tradeoffs involved in design choices.</item>
	  <item> (k) An ability to apply design and development principles in the construction of
	  software systems of varifying complexity.</item>
	</ABET-outcomes>
	<Learning-outcomes>
	  <item>Have the basic ideas regarding what is the difference between a population and a
	sample. be able to identify which is a representative sample and which is not</item>
	  <item>Be able to understand the difference between Statistics and Probability</item>
	  <item>Be able to represent given data through tables or pictures</item>
	  <item>Have the basic ideas of central tendencies and dispersions and will be able to use
	calculators to calculate them</item>
	  <item>Be able to get some heuristic ideas while looking at univariate and bivariate data
	and should be able to draw conclusions on the required parameters</item>
	  <item>Be able to calculate probabilities, moments etc. for various probability
	distributions (discrete or continuous).</item>
	  <item>Be able draw inferences related to studies involving one, two or more than two
	population means</item>
	  <item>Be able to draw inferences related to population variances</item>
	  <item>Be able to construct ANOVA tables and should have some basic ideas in
	experimental design</item>
	  <item>Have some basic ideas of correlation and linear regression</item>
	</Learning-outcomes>

</Course>
